UMAR KHAN PAGE 1

Umar Khan, PhD.

9 Curtis Road, Whitton, Middlesex TW4 5PU 07847 271 370

umar.khan.phd@gmail.com

Profile

CELTA and PTTLS qualified PhD graduate. Experienced in teaching ESOL/EFL and in the design and adaptation of undergraduate and graduate curricula for non-native English learners. Lecturing experience at higher education level with foreign students, in addition to teaching English to students age 18-21, and providing support to EAL students. Also, experienced in the area of economic and infrastructural risk analysis. Fluent in Arabic and Pashto.

Education

PhD, Politics & International Relations, Royal Holloway, University of London May 2011

Multi-disciplinary thesis adressing Economics and International Relations of Afghanistan, Pakistan and Central Asia. In-depth knowledge of research methodology, conceptual organisation, and academic language.

M.A. War Studies King's College, University of London

August 1999

Dissertation on the topic of 'Conflict Resolution over Water Rights in the Middle East'.

B.A. Political Science, California State University, Pomona

June 1997

Majored in Comparative Politics with minor in Economics and History. Honour Role and Dean's List.

CELTA & PTLLS, South Thames College, London

June 2013

Completed the Cambridge curriculum for English Teaching for Adults along with PTTLS qualification.

CRB - Clear – September 2013

Experience

English teaching (EFL) King Saud University, Riyadh, KSA

August 2013- September 2014

- . Taught four sections of Intermediate and pre-intermediate levels of EFL to undergraduate students.
- . Provided training in academic skills, research methods, and in-class IT skills using electronic learning tools
- . Carried out associated administrative and organisational responsibilities expected of an undergraduate teaching role including but not limited to attendance records, test generation, invigilation, and health and safety processes.

English Teaching – LIMA Centre

August 2009- July 2013, October 2014 – April 2017

Teaching Korean EFL students at lower intermediate, intermediate and upper intermediate levels in preparation for IELTS, and other academic exams.

Development of university credit course in conjunction with Derby University for vocational students.

Secretary of the LIMA Centre at time of departure.

Lecturer - University of London, Royal Holloway Dept. of Politics and International Relations London, UK September 2010 – August 2011

Taught three sections of undergraduate courses in the Department of Politics and International Relations

Provided academic English writing support to foreign students enrolled in the course

Employed multi-media means and group consulting styles in addition to lecturing and conventional teaching styles

Responsible for examination marking

Designed styles and means to facilitate effective learning among students with a range of abilities and backgrounds including special needs

Responsible for general administration related to the course.

UMAR KHAN PAGE 3

Curriculum development Consultant - Fullerton Consulting, Ltd

Projects undertaken as a consultant:

December 2009 – August 2010

Worked on preparing materials, curricula and teaching strategies for non-native English learners engaged in courses based on a programme generated by Oxford Brookes University.

Taught ESOL/EFL students learning English for academic objectives, citizenship tests, and functional skills.

Developed academic curriculum and updated existing curricula for vocational and performance arts institutions seeking academic accreditation and successfully liaised with Edexcel to create Ofqual approved vocational curricula for post-16 students.

Risk Analyst- Asia Exclusive Analysis, Ltd.

London, England

September 2003 -2011

Editing bi-weekly risk assessments covering all salient risk factors related to key Asian countries.

Editing on-going updates for Exclusive Analysis' web based product CREAM 7.0

Present research & analysis to clients and to conferences on behalf of Exclusive Analysis, including at the International Institute of Strategic Studies (IISS), London

Provide monthly assessments covering broader risk vectors in salient environments, and prognoses regarding likely short term risk trajectories.

Languages

English - Native speaker. **Pashto** - Spoken fluency.

Arabic - Spoken fluency with **Urdu** - Spoken fluency with reading.

reading and writing. Spanish - Spoken not fluent

.

References

Upon request